in today's video we are going to make
tiramisu ice cream in a ninja creamy
Deluxe this is another ninja creamy
recipe but you can only actually do this
one in the Ninja creamy Deluxe you could
absolutely make this in a normal machine
what we're going to do it's going to be
double layered so we're only going to
spin half of it let's do it or let's try
to yeah I love terisu
um it's really difficult to find a good
one there's lots of people that do kind
of like tiasu inspired ice creams I mean
Lots you know I've maybe had it twice
over the
last 30 plus years but it's not just
about having you know a coffee ice cream
mixed in with this that and the other
tiu is is also about the the texture the
the recipe of elements combined to
create something super super good and
there's a couple of things you need
obviously lady fingers I think I got
these in Safeway but you can get them on
Amazon in the UK you can literally get
them everywhere um and all over Europe
they're available in pretty much all
supermarkets so we're going to need some
of those we're going to need coffee and
we're going to need something to change
the freezing point depression of the
bottom layer we're going to do two
layers and the beauty
about the ninja creamy Deluxe the beauty
about the ninja creamy Deluxe is you can
actually just spin like the top part
half the whole thing or the bottom if
you're not going to fill the whole tub
up and we're going to use that to our
advantage here we're going to spin just
the top half so we're going to divide
this tub into actually three different
elements in the bottom we're going to
have our lady our coffee soaked lady
fingers with the freezing point adjusted
with
AOL we're then going to have a thin
layer of chocolate and that's going to
divide the two layers and then we're
going to do a cream cheese or masap pony
ice cream top and then what we're going
to do is we're going to put in another
little layer of chocolate on top of that
ice cream just before we spin it and as
we spin it it's going to create a
chocolate flecked masap Pony ice cream
top with our chocolate layer underneath
and then our hopefully not frozen solid
lady finger base sounds
complicated is so what are we going to
need I have no idea idea at this stage
so I think what we're going to do is
we're going to we're going to get some
coffee brewed up and we're going to get
some arrol mixed in
this vop
vop um this is just a rral and monk
fruit extract um it's mostly a rral um
so it's going to be super good for
depressing the freezing point of these
so let's get some coffee brewed up I use
a an espresso so let's do I don't know
let's I might do two of these tobs you
know make it worth doing these are 750 m
so I'm going to do 1.5 L of overall
product so let's start by doing four
Longo shots of espresso all right I only
did three shots three Longo shots that
gave me around
mL
of espresso
I don't think we need any more than that
so let's put that in here now see that
this loads that's fine probably could
have reduced that down to two lungos but
better to have too much than not enough
now I'm going to put the numbers on the
screen cuz I'm kind of winging this a
bit um we want to adjust the freezing
point of this liquid so that it doesn't
just turn to ice which it would do uh
and that's why we're using arrol so we
got 320
let's
do
four tablespoons
of this sugar
substitute and let's just stir that up
that will dissolve super super quick is
that enough I have no idea 6 12 18 24 so
it's about
20% by weight I
guess now we're going to take our Lids
off don't take this video as I know what
the hell I'm doing no idea for this
video at all I wanted to try something
different and here we are so lady
fingers if you don't know what they are
they're like super lightweight sponge
that's baked um to create a crispy kind
of uh
biscuit they're then dipped generally
with a sugar on top that's flavored with
I don't know actually something and you
get
this sugar all over me um and what we're
going to do is we're going to drop these
in here and then kind of get them in the
bottom of here just going to do these
one at a
time make sure they're really well
soaked there we go we're just starting
to lose structural Integrity this is
going to take me a while I'll come back
once this stage is done right I actually
did need another Longo shot so I needed
4 whatever it is
430 to 450 ml of coffee with what would
have five tablespoons of our Arial in it
that using an entire pack for these two
tubs so that's 2 4 6 8 10 12 12 lady
fingers if you wanted to add another
layer I'd say you probably could but
what we're going to do is we're going to
just pour some of that
coffee in cuz I kind of want a a layer
in the
bottom like that so if you don't like
coffee this one is not for you put these
in the
freezer for a few hours just to try and
get it nice and cold cuz the next layer
on top is going to be
chocolate so we're going to do a
cheesecake base mask bony is just way
too expensive at the moment due to the
economic fluctuations going on around
the world so we're going to use straight
cream cheese very standard for a
cheesecake this is 8 G fat per 30 G
I'm going to play around on here and
adjust the recipe to use xylol I want to
keep the sugar down in this
recipe um can't be sugar-free cuz the
lady fingers had sugar have sugar on top
um but obviously we've used arol to
balance the freezing point in our coffee
liquor so if we can keep this relatively
low in sugar jobs are good 5 minutes
later so after playing around on nice
cream calculated for the last 5 10
minutes I've made I've created a cream
cheese gelato so for that we are going
to need 244 G of straight fat cream
cheese 540 G of milk I'm using 2%
doesn't make any difference what milk
you use 79 G of xyl you can just use 80
G 35 G of skin milk powder and because
this is gelato we're going to use a
stabilizer we're going to use a hot
process stabilizer and we're going to
use 3 to 4 G of that if you use
something like gu then you might want to
drop it down zanon gum really bring that
down super gummy if you Ed Too Much sh
up so let's get everything ready in the
pan so the milk in the pan we're going
to cut up our cream cheese into just
slightly smaller lumps and that'll just
help it melt easier and let's get this
on the hob we're going to warm this up
right up to the temperature required for
our stabilizer which is 85c 185f I'll
come back once that's done at the start
it's going to be super thick and weird
to stir but just keep going and
eventually it will turn into this with
that heated up
we're going to put that in there it's
going to be a relatively thick base
because we've got a lot of the cream
cheese fat in
there and that is okay it's kind of
going to it's kind of going to look like
pudding what we're going to do is we're
going to put this into the fridge just
for an hour or two because we don't want
to melt that chocolate so that's what
we're doing we're trying to create
multiple layers that don't merge
together before we do that we're going
to add a teaspoon of vanilla bean paste
into
this nice right let's get this in the
fridge for a couple of hours to chill
down and then we'll start layering up I
took 50 g of chocolate this is a 60%
dark chocolate and one teaspoon of
deodorized coconut oil so refined
coconut oil melt melted that in the
microwave and then we took our Frozen
base out and actually it started to
freeze harder than I'd like so we
covered that with a very thin layer of
chocolate and then one set of Frozen
which pretty much much instantly we
topped it off with our ice cream base we
put that in the freezer and then after
that ice cream had gone hard in our tubs
we repeated that step with the chocolate
and put another very thin layer of
chocolate on top all right two tubs now
something to note
is I think the freezing point wasn't
affected Enough by the ariol at this
bottom
layer um and I can tell because it's
actually crept up which means the
expansion of the wall water has actually
taken place and that's why you get the
ninja creamy hump in the middle um
so I'm not going to give up so let's I
got a bowl of warm water there let's set
one is that going to go over the top
yep let's get some warm water in this
[Music]
bowl and we're going to sit that one
there
and see if we can soften that bottom
layer up we're going to
just see what happens so let's get the
bowl out of the way back
up let's take the first
one there is our chocolate top
nice let's see
how this one pans out full Tub light ice
cream
we still do have the Divide which is
which is really nice let's see if we can
get some kind of that bowl is not going
to cut it let's get this little bowl out
and see if we
can get two different
Scoops out of one tub
[Music]
all right well we didn't
get the result I
wanted and I think it it it adjustments
needed if we can adjust the bottom
layer's freezing point to keep it liquid
or semi
liquid um then this absolutely would
work the top layer of ice
cream which is this
one that's
delicious it's cream cheesy so
cheesecake kind of
taste you can taste that chocolate
running through
it that's
delicious the bottom scoop which is the
lady fingers soaked in
coffee oh that's good that's really
nice you got a bit of that ice cream
there it's not the result I wanted but
tell you
what two different Scoops out of one
tub and we got some chocolate survived
the spin
too it's melting super
fast I wanted to be able to take
something like that and go down the
middle and just take a Big Slice
of that out but that still worked really
nicely got to spin it on the light ice
cream setting on the ninja creamy Deluxe
and then youve got two different scoops
of ice cream you got the top half which
is a which is the cream cheese with that
really nice subtle kind of chocolate
Fleck through it then you've got pieces
of chocolate that break up on that
bottom layer and then you've got this
boss super B layer which is incredibly
coffee Rich it's got a different texture
too it's it's like a sbet texture on a
bottom of there that's really
interesting hey you know what like I
said it's not it's not the win that I
wanted but it's a it's a win all the
same I got another tub here which has
been sat in that water that warm water
and the bottom liquid melting but I
don't want to jeopardize the rest of it
so I'll just spin it like that one but
hey winner this is like like tiu ice
cream in shut up I can't really call
this a tiu cuz it's 100% not but this is
really good tiasu ice cream two layers
with chocolate in between ninja creamy
Deluxe give this one a try hope you
enjoyed this random take on frozen
desserts and I'll see you next week
[Music]